《行尸走肉》
瑞克 你…
Rick, just…
你一定要挺住
You've got to keep your strength up.
洛莉 你听说过…
Lori, did you…
我是说 这真是个传奇故事
I mean, it was legendary.
你听说过肖恩以前偷金斯利车的那件事吗
Did you ever hear about the time Shane stole Kingsley's car?
听说过
Yeah.
当时 校长的车
The principal's car.
就停在教职工停车场那儿
right out of the teacher's lot.
那还是学生时代的一个中午
in the middle of a school day.
肖恩出去吃午饭
Shane steps out of lunch and makes a beeline.
然后直奔金斯利的那辆现代
to Kingsley's Hyundai…
发动车 火速开动 沿着迪伦大道
Wires the ignition, peels out, drives down Dylan drive.
直奔那儿的一个养鸡场
to that chicken farm out there.
你以前听过这个故事的 对吧
You've heard this before, right?
他把那车停在一个很大的鸡舍里面
So he pulls it into one of the big holding pens.
金斯利每个月给那车打一次蜡
Kingsley, he waxed that thing every month;
每周送到车店里清理一遍
had the auto shop vacuum it out every week.
肖恩就把那车停在那个大鸡舍里
Shane, he parks it in this huge pen.
和几百只洛岛红鸡搁一块儿
with a couple of hundred rhode island reds.
他把车后座上装满种子的袋子撕开
He busts open bags of seed in the back seat,
把玻璃窗降下来
rolls down all the windows,
然后狂奔回学校
and then starts sprinting back to school.
那段路少说也有3英里远
It's three miles away easy.
他赶在上课铃响之前跑了回来 还吃完了三明治
He's back in time to finish his sandwich before the bell.
然后上课铃响了
And then the bell rings.
他在走廊里碰到了金斯利校长
Shane gets up and when he runs into Kingsley in the hallway.
他站起来 看着窗外说道
He looks out the window and says,
「金斯利校长
"Principal Kingsley,
你的坐骑不见了「
your coupe's gone."
坐骑 听着就跟说鸡舍似的
Coupe, like chicken coop.
我听懂了
I get it.
你当然听得懂
Of course you do.
这故事你都听了上千遍了
You've heard this story 1000 times.
之前的那些话 你说得对
What you said before, you're right.
肖恩会带着医生需要的东西回来的
Shane's gonna make it back with what the doctor needs.
他一定会平安回来的
He'll make it back.
赫谢尔说你需要吃些东西
Hershel said you need to eat.
卡尔不会有事的
Carl's gonna be all right.
求你了 就当是为了我
Please, for me.
你一定得挺住
You've got to keep your strength up.
我的弹夹呢
I need my clip now.
我要去路边 去找那小女孩
I'm gonna walk the road, look for the girl.
我也去
I'm coming too.
我去走走 在树林里面亮几束光
I'm going for a walk. Shine some light in the forest.
如果她在那儿 方便她看得到
If she's out there, give her something to look at.
- 你觉得现在这能算个好主意吗 - 戴尔
- You think that's a good idea right now? - Dale.
那边的几个窗户 外面是什么
Those windows, what's on the other side?
那窗户大概20英尺高
About a 20-foot drop with.
下面没有啥着落点 也许有些灌木丛
nothing to catch you, maybe some bushes,
- 然后就是运动场了 - 我们需要足够的时间
- Then the athletic field. - We just need enough time.
我们必须去那边 打开窗户 然后跳出去
We got to get up there. We got to get 'em open and get out.
我不行 也许你可以
Not me. Maybe you.
- 说什么呢 - 得了吧 你看我这体型
- Hey hey hey. - Come on, man, look at me.
你真觉得我能
You really think I can squeeze through.
从那么小的窗户眼儿挤出去
One of them tiny windows?
这些行尸都围着我们呢
They'd be all over us.
听着 我们得点几堆火 引他们过去
Look, we lay down some fire to get a head start.
你待在这儿 我跳下去把它们引开
You stay here. I hop down and draw them away.
这样你就有机会
That gives you the chance.
爬上那个看台 从窗户跳出去
to get up the bleachers and out a window.
那你去哪
And where do you go?
我去更衣室那边 就在那楼梯下面
Locker room down those steps.
在那好像很容易被困住
Looks like a good way to get trapped.
那里也有窗户 比较符合我的尺寸
It's got windows too, and more my size.
我从窗户钻出去 然后沿原路返回
I get out through one, I double back,
我们在外面碰面
we meet up out on the field.
你他妈真是疯了 是吧
You're a crazy son of a bitch, ain't you?
我只是想为那个小孩做点好事
Just trying to do right for that boy.
你对着它们放三枪 然后走人
You take three shots and you go.
然后我再开枪 掩护你
After that I fire. I'll lay down a cover for you.
- 给你引个路 - 好吧
- I'll get you a lead. - All right.
天哪
Oh god.
我们要按门铃吗
So do we ring the bell?
我觉得这里好像住着人
I mean it looks like people live here.
我们不必多此一举了 好吗
We're past this kind of stuff, aren't we?
已经很善解人意了
Having to be considerate.
你们开车进来时关上大门了吗
Did you close the gate up the road when you drove in?
你好
Uh, hi.
我们关了
Yes, we closed it.
插了门闩 都关好了
Did the latch and everything.
你好 很高兴再次见到你
Hello. Nice to see you again.
我们之前简短地打过照面
We met before briefly.
我们是来帮忙的 有需要我们做的吗
Look, we came to help. There anything we can do?
不是咬伤 我自己不小心割伤的很严重
It's not a bite. I cut myself pretty bad though.
我们得好好看看
We'll have it looked at.
我去告诉他们你们来了
I'll tell them you're here.
我这儿有些止痛药和抗生素
We have some painkillers and antibiotics.
已经给他吃了一些
I already gave him some.
如果卡尔需要就拿去吧
If Carl needs any.
快进来 我给你们做点吃的
Come on inside. I'll make you something to eat.
有我们在 没事的
Um, we're here, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
需要什么尽管说
Whatever you need.
他们还不赶紧回来
They don't get back soon,
我们就得做个决定了
we're gonna have a decision to make.
什么决定
And that is?
在没有呼吸机的情况下
Whether to operate on your boy.
要不要给你们的儿子动手术
without the respirator.
- 你说过这行不通的 - 我知道
- You said that wouldn't work. - I know.
这确实不大可能 但我们不能多等了
It's extremely unlikely. But we can't wait much longer.
你真觉得我们会找到索菲亚吗
You really think we're gonna find Sophia?
你脸上的表情
You got that look on your face.
跟其他人没两样
same as everybody else.
你们这些人到底怎么了
What the hell's wrong with you people?
- 我们才刚开始找呢 - 是吗
- We just started looking. - Well, do you?
这又不是在西藏的某座山上
It ain't the mountains of Tibet.
这是乔治亚州
It's Georgia.
她可能在某个农家小屋待着
She could be holed up in a farmhouse somewhere.
人们迷路 又幸存下来
People get lost and they survive.
- 这种事时有发生 - 她才十二岁
- It happens all the time. - She's only 12.
见鬼 我走丢的时候比她还小呢
Hell, I was younger than her and I got lost.
在丛林里九天 就吃浆果度日
Nine days in the woods eating berries,
用毒橡树叶擦屁股
Wiping my ass with poison oak.
他们后来找到你了吗
They found you?
我老爸和女招待去饮酒作乐
My old man was off on a bender with some waitress.
莫尔被关在少管所里
Merle was doing another stint in juvie.
都没发现我不见了
Didn't even know I was gone.
我自己找到了回来的路
I made my way back though.
直接去厨房给自己做了个三明治
Went straight into the kitchen and made myself a sandwich.
好像什么都没发生过一样
No worse for wear.
除了我的屁股痒得死去活来
Except my ass itched something awful.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
抱歉 你的故事真凄惨
I'm sorry, that is a terrible story.
唯一不同的是 索菲亚起码还有人去找
Only difference is Sophia's got people looking for her.
这就是有利的地方
I call that an advantage.
或许这不再是孩子们的世界了
Maybe this isn't a world for children anymore.
我们有孩子
Yeah well, we have a child.
卡尔在此时生在这个世界
Carl is here in this world now.
或许他不该出生的
Maybe he shouldn't be.
或许这是命中注定的
Maybe is is how it's supposed to be.
你不会是认真的吧
You can't mean that.
好吧 好吧
Okay. All right.
我能理解你 那念头一闪而过
I can understand that thought crossing your mind.
这不是一闪而过的 瑞克
It didn't cross my mind, Rick.
我忍不住一直在想
I can't stop thinking it.
我们为什么要让卡尔活在这样的世界
Why do we want Carl to live in this world?
过着这样的生活
To have this life?
让他亲眼看到更多人被撕成碎片吗
So he can see more people torn apart in front of him?
为了让他挨饿 还担惊受怕
So that he can be hungry and scared.
一直到他被…
For however long he has before he…
他能做的除了逃 还是逃
So he can run and run and run and run.
即使最后幸存下来
And then even if he survives he ends up…
结果也不过是成为另一个
He ends up just another.
除了生存什么也不知道的行尸罢了
animal who doesn't know anything except survival?
如果他
If he…
如果他今晚没撑过去
If he dies tonight,
对他来说就解脱了
It ends for him.
你倒是说啊 为什么活着更好啊
Tell me why it would be better another way.
是什么改变了
What changed?
你说什么
What?
詹纳曾给我们指了条出路
Jenner offered us a way out.
你求他让我们继续尝试下去
You asked him to let us keep trying.
你恳求他
You begged him.
你说「要尽我们所能」
"For as long as we can."
是什么改变了你的想法
You said. What changed?
有一天 某一刻
There was a moment the other day…
就那么一秒钟 我忘了杰奎已经去世
It was just a second but I forgot Jacqui was dead.
我转过身想和她说点什么
I turned around, I wanted to tell her something.
我几乎叫出来她的名字了
I almost said her name.
It was just a second and then I remembered.
然后我意识到她再也不用看这些
But then I realized she didn't have to see any of it.
公路 尸群 索菲亚 卡尔受枪伤
The highway, the herds, sophia, carl getting shot…
她不…
She didn't…
她用不着再害怕了
She doesn't have to be afraid anymore.
饥饿 愤怒
Hungry. Angry.
时刻伴随 瑞克
It hasn't stopped happening, Rick.
就像每时每刻
It's like we live with a.
都有一把刀架在我们的脖子上
knife at our throats every second of every day.
但杰奎不用这么活 再也不用了
But Jacqui doesn't. Not anymore.
然后
And then…
我想 也许詹纳是对的
I thought, "Maybe Jenner was right."
我不这样认为
I don't accept that.
我无法接受
I can't accept that.
他认命了 他不
That man surrendered. It doesn't matt…
他的话没有意义
It doesn't matter what he said.
没有一点意义
None of it.
如果卡尔…如果我们就这么放弃
You really think it would be better if Carl…
你真的认为这样更好吗
If we just gave up?
你告诉我 如果不这样的话会好到哪去
Tell me why it would be better the other way.
告诉我
Please.
老兄 我以为你死了
Man, I thought I'd lost you.
这是我最后一个弹匣
That was my last rifle round.
- 我也是 - 快走
- Mine too. - Come on.
快走 快点
Come on. Come on.
- 我们在哪 - 嘿 小家伙
- Where are we? - Hey, little man.
这位是赫谢尔
That's Hershel.
我们在他家里
We're in his house.
你出了点意外
You had an accident.
- 好点了吗 - 疼 非常疼
- All right? - It hurts, a lot.
宝贝 我知道 我知道
Oh baby, I know. I know.
- 你真应该亲眼看看 - 什么
- You should have seen it. - What?
那只鹿
The deer.
它特别美 妈妈
It was so pretty, mom.
离我很近
It was so close.
我从来都没
I've never been…
卡尔
Carl?
他怎么了
What is happening?
不要动他 是癫痫发作
Don't. It's a seizure.
如果按住他 会伤到他的
If you hold him down, you could hurt him.
不能让它停下来吗
You can't stop it?
他必须自己挺过去
He has to just go through it.
他大脑供血不足
His brain isn't getting enough blood.
血压太低了 需要再输一次血
His pressure is bottoming. He needs another transfusion.
- 好 来抽吧 - 如果你再失血的话
- Okay, I'm ready. - If I take any more out of you.
你身体会受不住的 可能会昏迷
your body could shut down. You could go into a coma.
- 或者心跳暂停 - 别浪费时间了
- Or cardiac arrest. - You're wasting time.
快来 老兄 我们得离开这
Come on, man. We need a way out.
- 让我喘口气 - 快来
- Just let me catch my breath. - Come on.
睡不着
Can't sleep?
我要等他们回来
I'm gonna wait for them to come back.
你愿意的话 可以下去睡会
You can go down and sleep if you want to.
不了 我们一块等
No, we can keep watch together.
他们往哪个方向走了
Which way did they go?
老天
What the hell?
「被咬了 发高烧
"Got bit. Fever hit.
世界太恐怖了 我还是退出吧「
World gone to shit. Might as well quit."
这蠢货都不知道得射脑袋才行
Dumbass didn't know enough to shoot himself in the head.
把自己挂在树上 变成招摇的诱饵
Turned himself into a big swinging piece of bait.
真是一团糟
And a mess.
你还好吧
You all right?
努力不吐出来
Trying not to puke.
- 想吐就吐吧 - 不 我没事
- Go ahead if you gotta. - No, I'm fine.
我们聊点别的
Let's just talk about something else for a minute.
- 你是怎么学会射击的 - 我得吃饭
- How'd you learn to shoot? - Gotta eat.
这是我们和行尸的共同之处
That's one thing these walkers and us have in common.
我想这是他变行尸后第一次离食物这么近
I guess it's the closest he's been to food since he turned.
他挂在那 好像一个大皮纳塔（墨西哥玩具）
Hanging up there like a big pinata.
其他行尸把他腿上的肉都给吃了
The other geeks came and ate all the flesh off his legs.
我以为咱们换了话题的
I thought we were changing the subject.
这就是笑我屁股痒的代价
Call that payback for laughing about my itchy ass.
那事不经常发生
There wasn't a lot that came up.
我们回去吧
Let's head back.
你不
Aren't you gonna…
不 他不会伤害其他人
No. He ain't hurting nobody.
不值得费一支箭
Ain't gonna waste an arrow either.
他做出了自己的选择 退出了
He made his choice. Opted out.
让他在那挂着吧
Let him hang.
你想要继续活着吗
You want to live now or not?
只是问问
It's just a question.
我回答你 你射死他
An answer for an arrow.
公平吧
Fair?
我不知道自己想不想要活着
I don't know if I want to live.
或者有没有必要活下去
Or if I have to.
也许活着只是一种习惯
Or if it's just a habit.
这个答案不怎么样
Not much of an answer.
浪费一支箭
Waste of an arrow.
你不用担心 她和达里尔在一起
You don't need to worry. She's with daryl.
要是有危险他会保护她的
If something happens he can protect her.
你听到我说的了吗
You hear what I'm saying?
抱歉 我只听到如果有事发生
Sorry, all I heard was if something happens.
你帮我看会儿
You mind keeping watch?
我不会用枪
I don't know how to use that.
我一会儿就回来
I won't be gone long.
如果你发现情况就大叫
If you see anything, call out.
我不会走远的 听得见你
I'm not going far. I'll hear you.
你来得真及时
You got here right in time.
再不救治你就不行了
This couldn't go untreated much longer.
莫尔·迪克森
"Merle Dixon."
这抗生素的主人是你们的朋友
Is that your friend with the antibiotics?
不 太太 莫尔不跟我们在一起了
No, ma'am. Merle's no longer with us.
这是达里尔给的 他弟弟
Daryl gave us those… his brother.
我可不确定他算不算朋友
Not sure I'd call him a friend.
今天一定是 强力霉素今天救了你一命
He is today. This doxycycline might have just saved your life.
你知道莫尔为什么吃这个
You know what Merle was taking it for?
淋病
The clap.
性病
Um, venereal disease.
达里尔说的
That's what Daryl said.
莫尔·迪克森的淋病
I'd say Merle Dixon's clap.
是你最好的礼物
was the best thing to ever happen to you.
我可不要这么想
I'm really trying not to think about that.
你在祈祷吗
Are you praying?
为什你老爱偷看别人
Why do you sneak up on people so much?
你很容易被人偷看
You're easy to sneak up on.
我是在祈祷
I was praying.
我在尝试祈祷
I was trying to.
你信教吗 你常常祈祷吗
You religious? You pray a lot?
其实这是我第一次
Actually this was my first try.
以前没有
Ever?
抱歉
Wow. Sorry.
我不是故意来搅黄你的第一次的
I didn't mean to wreck your first time.
上帝大概已经收到了
God probably got the gist.
- 你为什么祈祷 - 为我的朋友们
- Praying for what? - My friends.
看起来他们现在都挺需要帮助
Looks like they could all use a little help right now.
你认为…
You think…
你认为上帝真的存在吗
You think god exists?
我以前非常相信
I always took it on faith.
最近我开始怀疑
Lately I've wondered.
你看发生的这一切
Everything that's happened,
肯定大家一直都在祈祷
there must have been a lot of praying going on.
但上帝并没给予多少答复
It seems quite a few went unanswered.
谢谢 你还真帮了我
Thanks. This is really helping.
抱歉 你继续
Sorry. Go ahead.
真的
Really.
你还要看着
You gonna watch?
我去帮你倒水
I'll get you a refill instead.
我知道这不关我的事
I know it's not my business,
信不信上帝是个人自由
and feel free to believe in god,
但是不管情况有多糟糕 你都要
but the thing is you've got to make it okay somehow.
自己想办法解决问题
no matter what happens.
他中枪前
Before it happened.
我们站在丛林里
we were standing there in the woods.
有头鹿
And this deer.
走到我们面前
just crossed right in front of us.
我发誓它就站在那儿一动不动
I swear it just planted itself there.
紧紧盯着卡尔看
and looked Carl right in the eye.
我看着卡尔
And I looked at Carl.
卡尔看着鹿 鹿也看着卡尔
looking at that deer, and that deer looking right back at Carl.
那个瞬间只是…
And that moment just…
刹那而过
slipped away.
It slipped away.
他醒来就谈起这一瞬间
That's what he was talking about when he woke up,
而不是中枪
not about getting shot.
或是教堂里的事
or what happened at the church.
他说的是美好的事情
He talked about something beautiful,
有生命力的东西
something living.
我们还能有美好生活
There's still a life for us,
一个像这样的地方
a place maybe like this.
还没到死绝的地步
It isn't all death out there.
还没有
It can't be.
我们必须坚强一点
We just have to be strong enough.
经历这些以后我们还可以相信奇迹
After everything we've seen to still believe that.
你问我为什么卡尔活着比较好
Why is it better for Carl to live even in this world?
他谈起了那头鹿 洛莉
He talked about the deer, lori.
他竟然谈起了那头鹿
He talked about the deer.
必须走到街上 然后返回到卡车那
Got to get to the street, double back to the truck.
- 我们到不了了 - 那也得试试 伙计
- Look, we ain't gonna make it, okay? - Got to try, man.
- 加油 起来 - 你来拿这些包
- Come on, get up. - You're gonna take these bags.
- 然后往前走 - 我不会丢下你
- And you're gonna go. - I ain't leaving you behind.
好吧
Okay.
你还有几发子弹
How many rounds you got left?
四发 你呢
Four. You?
五发 还有一发在枪膛里
Five and one in the pipe.
他失血的速度比我们补充的还快
He's still losing blood faster than we can replace it.
而且他腹腔积水
And with the swelling in his abdomen,
我们不能再等了
we can't wait any longer.
否则他会没命的
Or he's just going to slip away.
我现在必须知道
Now I need to know right now,
你们是否希望我动刀
if you want me to do this.
因为我觉得这孩子时间不多了
Because I think your boy is out of time.
你们必须做出选择
You have to make a choice.
- 选择 - 选择
- A choice? - A choice.
你必须告诉我怎么做
You have to tell me what it is.
动手术吧
We do it.
好 都站到床角
Okay, get the corner of that bed.
把床单扯下来
Let's get the sheets down.
输液袋放到床单上
Get the I.V. bag on the sheet.
好
Okay.
我数到三
On three.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
瑞克 洛莉
Rick, Lori,
你们还是回避一下吧
you may want to step out.
谢天谢地
Oh god.
你留下来看着他
You stay here with him.
- 卡尔怎样了 - 还有救
- Carl? - There's still a chance.
奥蒂斯呢
Otis?
没逃出来
No.
别告诉帕特里夏
We say nothing to Patricia.
事后再说 我现在需要她
Not till after. I need her.
每个拐弯都有行尸围堵
They kept blocking us at every turn.
我们弹尽粮绝 只剩十发子弹
We had nothing left. We were down to 10 rounds.
然后他说 他说他掩护我
Then he said… he said he'd cover me,
叫我继续往前走
that I should keep going.
所以我就这么做了 我只是…
So that's what I did. I just…
我继续向前 可我…
I kept going. But I…
我回头看 而他…
I looked back and he…
我尽力了
I tried.
他是想弥补自己的过错
He wanted to make it right.
安德莉亚 等会儿
Andrea. Wait.
戴尔 你又想干嘛
What do you want, Dale?
给你这个
To give you this.
我关心你
I care about you.
所以才替你做了那个决定 那些决定
So I made a choice for you… choices.
我知道我为何这么做 但这不是我的枪
I know why I did it, but this is not my gun.
而且那些我替你做的决定
And the choices that I made for you.
也不该由我来做
were not mine to make.
但我还是要说
But I can still ask.
这不是要让你内疚
And this is not to make you guilty,
也不是要抬高我自己 但我还是要说
Or put me ahead of you, but I can still ask,
请你…
Please…
别让我后悔这么做
Don't make me regret this.
我来放哨
I'll take watch.
那你原谅我…
So do you forgive me for…
你原谅我吗
Do you forgive me?
我尽量
I'm trying.
我从小就认识奥蒂斯
I've known Otis since I was a kid.
我母亲去世前 他就在打理这个农场了
He's run this farm since before my mother died.
还有谁
Who else?
你还失去了谁
Who'd you lose?
你说过我得自己想办法解决问题
You told me I had to make it okay somehow.
你也一直在努力这么做 对吗
That's what you've been trying to do, right?
哪些人
Which ones?
继母
Stepmother.
同父异母的兄弟
Stepbrother.
看来他病情已经稳定了
He seems to have stabilized.
感谢老天
Oh god.
我不知道要说什么好
I don't have words.
我也是 真希望我知道
I don't either. Wish I did.
我该怎么和帕特里夏说奥蒂斯的事
How do I tell Patricia about Otis?
你去看卡尔
You go to Carl.
我和赫谢尔去
I'll go with Hershel.
别走
Stay.
浴室在楼上
The bathroom's upstairs.
- 我给你找了些衣服 - 谢谢
- I brought you some clothes. - Thank you.
衣服不太合身 是奥蒂斯的衣服
They won't fit well. They were Otis's.
你还剩几发子弹
How many rounds you got left?
四发 你呢
Four. You?
五发 还有一发上膛了
Five and one in the pipe.
加油
Come on.
- 我就剩一发了 - 我也是
- Down to my last. - Me too.
对不起了
I'm sorry.
还不放手
Will you give it… ah!
放手
Give it!
我要宰了你
I'll kill you.
放开我 放手
Let go of me! Let go!